<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An artificiall apologie, articulerly [sic] answerynge to the obstreperous obgannynges of one W.G. euometyd to the vituperacion of the tryumphant trollynge Thomas Smyth / repercussed by the ryght redolent &amp; rotounde rethorician R. Smyth, P. with annotacio[n]s of the mellifluous and misticall Master Mynterne, marked in the mergent for the enucliacion of certen obscure obelisques, to thende that the imprudent lector shulde not tytubate or hallucinate in the labyrinthes of the lucubratiuncle.</title>
            <author>Smyth, R.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1540</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 11 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A12556</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 22877.6</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S2988</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">29633095</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 29633095</idno>
            <idno type="VID">28048</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A12556)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 28048)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1861:10)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An artificiall apologie, articulerly [sic] answerynge to the obstreperous obgannynges of one W.G. euometyd to the vituperacion of the tryumphant trollynge Thomas Smyth / repercussed by the ryght redolent &amp; rotounde rethorician R. Smyth, P. with annotacio[n]s of the mellifluous and misticall Master Mynterne, marked in the mergent for the enucliacion of certen obscure obelisques, to thende that the imprudent lector shulde not tytubate or hallucinate in the labyrinthes of the lucubratiuncle.</title>
                  <author>Smyth, R.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Imprynted at London by Rycharde Bankes. Cum priuilegio ad imprimendum solum. And to be sell [sic] in Pater noster rowe at the signe of the Rose,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1540]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>In verse.</note>
                  <note>Includes marginal notes in Latin.</note>
                  <note>Publication date from STC (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Society of Antiquaries.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Smyth, Thomas, --  servaunt to the Quenes most excellent Majestie.</term>
               <term>Gray, William.</term>
               <term>Ballads, English.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  London (England) --  16th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-05</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-05</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb facs="tcp:28048:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>¶ An artificiall Apologie, articulerlye anſwerynge to the obſtreperous Obgannynges of one W. G. Euometyd to the vituperacion of the tryumphant trollynge Thomas ſmyth. Repercuſſed by the ryght redolent &amp; rotounde rethorician R. Smyth P. with annotacio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s of the mellifluous and miſticall Maſter Mynterne, marked in the mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent for the enucliacion of certen obſcure obeliſques, to thende that the imprudent lector ſhulde not tytubate or halluci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate in the labyrinthes of this lucubratiuncle.</head>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">M</seg>Oued wyth mercy, by pytye prouoked</l>
               <l>Of duty I am dryue<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, ſomwhat for to wryte</l>
               <l>In defence of one, whome I ſe ſore boked <note place="margin">Pietas in potentes.</note>
               </l>
               <l>And ſore aſſauted, to be beaten fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> the ryght</l>
               <l>But yf I lyue, ſome of them ſhalbe ſmoked</l>
               <l>His part wyl I take w<hi rend="sup">t</hi> al my power &amp; myght. <note place="margin">Ot decet hetetioos.</note>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>My harte doth blede, to ſe my frende thus dreaſt</l>
               <l>So that my penne wyll wryte, though I ſaye naye</l>
               <l>I gaynſt this brothyſhe graye, this bytter bytyng beaſt</l>
               <l>That ſeketh nothynge elles, but for to pull awaye</l>
               <l>The good name and fame, of one that is honeſt</l>
               <l>And ful of lytterature, as all that loue hym ſaye <note place="margin">Alii, aliter.</note>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Maſter Thomas ſmyth, his name nede not be hyd</l>
               <l>Whome to ſe ſo handled, I haue great remorſe</l>
               <l>For the ſtockes ſake, of which he is deſcended</l>
               <l>He commeth of the ſmyth, that ſhed ſaynt Georges horſſe</l>
               <l>By ryght deſſent, it maye not be denyed</l>
               <l>But yf any wolde, it ſhall not greatly force. <note place="margin">Zans generis.</note>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Who made this bagnrde ſo bolde, this greſely graye</l>
               <l>Or what heart hath he, that he thus aſſayles</l>
               <l>Our ſmyths, yf S. Georges horſſe were a lyue I ſaye</l>
               <l>He dorſt euen as well haue eaten both his nayles</l>
               <l>But though he be gone, all beaſtes be not awaye</l>
               <l>I coulde ſaye more, but he doth naught that rayles. <note place="margin">Dinſi<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> a<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> c.</note>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Betwyxt the ſmythes &amp; grayes, no doute ther is great oddes</l>
               <l>Loke in vitas patrum, I ſaye thou wylfull wagge</l>
               <l>Howe ſmyths haue bene byſhoppes, ſaynts &amp; almoſt goddes</l>
               <l>Recorde of ſwete ſaynt Loye, that holpe a cloyed nagge <note place="margin">Witatulum.</note>
               </l>
               <l>Mulcant was god &amp; ſmith, whoſe curſe lyghte on thy coddes</l>
               <l>Why then with vs ſmythes, art thou ſo bolde to bragge</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Marke this malycious, and ſore bytynge broch</l>
               <l>Becauſe maſter ſmyth, called him theſe in ſporte</l>
               <l>Speakynge it but merely, I dare ſaye in mock <note place="margin">In bono ioco.</note>
               </l>
               <l>Howe lewdely of him, he hath made reporte</l>
               <l>But ſaye what thou canſt, he dyd it not by cock</l>
               <l>For by ſaynt tankarde, he is none of that ſorte. <note place="margin">Nota ꝙ non po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teſt portate ſet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uiſiam.</note>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The money &amp; the woma<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, wherwith thou doeſt him charge</l>
               <l>He maye full well aduoyde, it is no great thynge</l>
               <l>God ſaue the kynge, a pardon doth dyſcharge <note place="margin">Miſericordias <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>n<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>i ineternum cantabo. Id eſt cibus pro pauperibus d<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> nou<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> porto.</note>
               </l>
               <l>Mo thynges then that, which elles myght hap to brynge</l>
               <l>Both him and you, but ſkant to walke at large</l>
               <l>Within an yron grate, your Chriſtmas ſonge to ſynge</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>As for the woman, alas it was no wonder</l>
               <l>She was a whore, and he hath ſuch a charme <note place="margin">A ſpiritu for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nicationis &amp;c.</note>
               </l>
               <l>If ſhe be arrant, to brynge her ſhortly vnder</l>
               <l>And yet I promyſe you, he doth them lytle harme</l>
               <l>But bryngs them to his houſe, where they parte not aſonder</l>
               <l>He couereth her, he colleth her &amp; keps her good and Warme. <note place="margin">Amor vincit ola.</note>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And forſoth full well, towarde his olde dayes</l>
               <l>Ye poynted him a place, to be in the ſtable</l>
               <l>But he neuer dreſſed horſſe, as he him ſelfe ſayca <note place="margin">We hoc docto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>res dubicant.</note>
               </l>
               <l>Wherfore for that rome, he is nothynge able</l>
               <l>His lyuynge he muſt ſeke, by ſome other wayes</l>
               <l>Well ynough I warrant you, without hode or bable</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>If he had no maſter, ner none wolde him take</l>
               <l>Skant into the ſtable, yet ere it were longe</l>
               <l>He hath ſo many frendes, thou ſayeſt wolde ſhyft make</l>
               <l>To promote him to the ſkourynge, of ſome good ma<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s gonge <note place="margin">Melior eſt ami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cos in curin, qua<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> denatius in bur<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſa.</note>
               </l>
               <l>Thou art to ſpytefull, and I for anger ſhake</l>
               <l>To ſe howe thou doeſt, this poore man ſo much wronge.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Ye call him papiſt, becauſe ye ſe him worche</l>
               <l>In all he doth or ſayth, by doctours and decrees</l>
               <l>Of our olde auncyent mother holy churche</l>
               <l>And for bycauſe, he doth defende theyr dygnytyes <note place="margin">Diſtingus de eccleſ<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>.</note>
               </l>
               <l>Lyke a ſorte of lorrelles, you wolde him geue a lurche</l>
               <l>His credyte and his fame, to cauſe hym for to leſe.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Our ſmyth can forge, and fetely fabrycate <note place="margin">Qnod natuta debit, nemo collere poteſt.</note>
               </l>
               <l>A myllyon of mentyres, in leſſe then halfe a daye</l>
               <l>Loke in all his workes which are conſolydate</l>
               <l>Lyke a wyttye man, dawe canſt thou ſaye naye?</l>
               <l>In ſuch an honeſt forge, lo he was educate</l>
               <l>And ſuch his bryngynge vp, his craft cannot decaye <note place="margin">Experien<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tia decet.</note>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And yet this bytynge brocke, ſayes he is vnworthy <note place="margin">De homini illi per quem ſcan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daliun venit.</note>
               </l>
               <l>To be a paryſhe clercke, God geue the wo and care</l>
               <l>But yer he come therto, we truſt to ſe the lye</l>
               <l>Aſkynge for gods ſake, in pouertie full bare</l>
               <l>Wylt thou pare with our ſmyth, ah pylde pratynge pye <note place="margin">Per ſyn<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>open quaſi dicitur compare.</note>
               </l>
               <l>Well do not ſo I aduyſe you, I councell you beware.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>It wylbe a good whyle or you maſter Graye</l>
               <l>Haue ſuch qualylytes as maſter Smyth hath <note place="margin">Nota donum linguatum.</note>
               </l>
               <l>He ſpeketh euen as good frenche, I dare well ſaye</l>
               <l>As any Popengay, betwene this and bathe</l>
               <l>Cracke me that nut, naye fye I praye you awaye</l>
               <l>Medle not withall, leaſt that it doth, you ſkathe.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Syr he hath bene in Parys, farre beyonde the ſee <note place="margin">Didit plus qu<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> mandneam<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> per &amp;c.</note>
               </l>
               <l>where thou durſt neuer, yet pepe out of thy dore</l>
               <l>And I my ſelfe, dyd here him once ſaye</l>
               <l>With ſo ſtarne a loke, Dieu vous donc bon iour</l>
               <l>That euer ſence, I thought hym ryght well worthy</l>
               <l>To haue the lytle roume, within the kynges toute</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Hercules was ſtronger, then any of the grayes</l>
               <l>Yet was he not hable to mache with two at once</l>
               <l>Beware I ſaye thou brocke and ſhortely walke thy wayes <note place="margin">Waree ei <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>, nihil eni ſunt dicscius.</note>
               </l>
               <l>For we be many ſmythes, and yf we catche the once</l>
               <l>We wyll fynde the meanes, to ſhorten thy good dayes</l>
               <l>And in our flammyng forge, we wil burne the fleſhe &amp; bones.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Becant therfore betyme, leaſt w<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>e the momorde <note place="margin">Bonum co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                     <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>lium.</note>
               </l>
               <l>And beate the with oure handes, as yron the ſtyth</l>
               <l>Cauſynge the for euer, to be a good recorde</l>
               <l>Howe any man herafter doth rayle vpon a ſmyth <note place="margin">Cauete a fabris quorua<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> multi.</note>
               </l>
               <l>Thy fame we ſhall pollute, for ſowenge ſoch diſcord</l>
               <l>Maugre all theyr heartes, that be diſpleaſed therwith.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>I warrant you thys graye, hath lytle good maner</l>
               <l>To call maſter ſmyth, bedlem and lunatycke</l>
               <l>What though he be gogle eyed, and tawny as atanner <note place="margin">Nota ꝙ chole, rici ſu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t itacſidia <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>m Auio<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>. c. viii.</note>
               </l>
               <l>It is but hys compleceyon, ſwart and collerycke</l>
               <l>But ſythen that he doth fyght, vnder holy churches baner</l>
               <l>His lybels are allowed, for good and catholycke.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And though he be a ſmyth, by face and eke of name</l>
               <l>Yet to God and the kyng, the man maye be wellwylled</l>
               <l>For was not there a ſmyth that propre feates dyd frame</l>
               <l>The chronycles make mencyon, whoſo them well behylde</l>
               <l>Reporte me to the blacke ſmyth, a man of worthy fame <note place="margin">In memoria ete<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> na erit inſtus.</note>
               </l>
               <l>Howe many at his co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>maundeme<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t, had he at blackheth felde.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Nowe for that ſmyth, &amp; all ſmythes y<hi rend="sup">t</hi> mean as he dyd mean <note place="margin">v. Pater noſter. v. Ane Maria. vnum Cred<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>n De pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fundis.</note>
               </l>
               <l>Or that agaynſt God and our kynge, ought conſpyre or ſaye</l>
               <l>That ſuch of there offenſes, maye be confeſſed cleane</l>
               <l>And iuſt rewarde to take, this prayer wyll I praye</l>
               <l>And alſo that all other, that to theyr ſectes do leane</l>
               <l>Maye trudge w<hi rend="sup">t</hi> the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> for co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>pany, to angre Wyllyam Graye.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Thus forced by frendſhyp, and lykenes of name</l>
               <l>I haue compyled this brefe apologye <note place="margin">Quia ſunt de vno cognoic.</note>
               </l>
               <l>Propungnyng therin ſmythes, and theyr honeſt fame</l>
               <l>And theyr vylependers, to ſhame and turpefye</l>
               <l>Implorynge, that Lorde, that forged the frame <note place="margin">
                     <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> aucthor <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>otu <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>at i<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> 
                     <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ethori<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>s.</note>
               </l>
               <l>Of fyre and water, of earth and of ſkye.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>To preſerue Kynge Henry that prynce potencyall</l>
               <l>And Katheryne oure quene of curteſye the floure</l>
               <l>Wyth Edwarde oure prince, that ympe emperyall</l>
               <l>In helth, in welth, in ryches, in honour,</l>
               <l>And to conſerue the counſell heroical</l>
               <l>To pauyſe the people by prudencyall power.</l>
            </lg>
            <closer>God ſaue the Kynge.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>¶ Imprynted at London by Rycharde Bankes. <hi>Cum priuilegio ad imprimendum ſolum.</hi> And be to ſell in Pater noſter rowe, at the ſygne of the Roſe.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
